impacttourcenter.com 2014-06-27

# Use of private information - Privacy policy | Brightspark Travel

This Privacy Policy describes the privacy practices of Educatours, Ltd., dba as Brightspark and Breakaway tours, (“Brightspark Travel”, “We” or “us”). Brightspark Travel is a student tour operator specializing in trips for college and high school students. Brightspark Travel holds TICO Registration Numbers 2267878 and 2422707.

By accessing and using this website, you agree and consent (and your parent/legal guardian agrees and consents on your behalf, if you are under the age of majority in your jurisdiction of residence) to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information as outlined in this Policy.

If you have any questions about this Policy, please contact us as indicated in the _How to Contact Us_ section below. We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time, so please check this Privacy Policy periodically for changes. Your continued access or use of this website after any such changes constitutes your acceptance (and the acceptance of your parent/legal guardian on your behalf, if you are under the age of majority in your jurisdiction of residence) of the Privacy Policy as revised.

This Privacy Policy applies to our websites located at [www.brightsparktravel.ca](http://www.brightsparktravel.ca/) and [www.breakawaytours.com](http://www.breakawaytours.com/) and any of our other sites that link to this Privacy Policy. We refer to all of these sites as the “Website.”

We collect two basic types of information: personal information and anonymous information. We define “personal information” as information that is about an identifiable individual. Personal information might include: names, ages, contact information, payment information, school affiliation and travel schedule and preferences. “Anonymous information” is information that does not identify you, such as technical information about your computer or anonymous statistical information about groups of our users.

We collect both personal information and anonymous information through the Website. We sometimes collect personal information and anonymous information by asking you to enter it into forms on our Website. For example, if you make a request for more information about one of our trips, we request your name, e-mail, phone number, the name of your school and other details.  We also collect anonymous information automatically as you use the Website—see the section below titled Cookies and Analytics.

If we do receive your personal information, we will only use it for the purposes described where it is collected or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. For example, we may use the personal information you provide to:

  * respond to your questions or comments- for example, if you request more information about a trip, we will use your contact details to send you that information.
  * administer our promotions and Website;
  * fulfill your purchase, subscription or order;
  * to otherwise provide or improve our products and services; and/or
  * to carry out other purposes which are disclosed to you and to which you consent.

We will not share your personal information with third-parties unless:

  * you give us your express permission to do so;
  * it is to your parent or guardian if you are a minor;
  * it is to your trip organizer, if you are part of a group trip; you, or your parent or guardian if you are a minor, consent to this by participating in a group trip;
  * it is necessary to allow our service providers or agents to provide services for us;
  * it is necessary in order to provide you with our products or services that you have requested or to contact you;
  * it is to other subsidiaries of TUI Travel PLC, for the purposes described in this Policy;
  * subject to applicable contractual or legal restrictions, it is disclosed to entities that perform marketing services on our behalf or to other entities with whom we have joint marketing agreements;
  * in connection with the sale, merger, or acquisition of our business;
  * it is necessary to process payments from you;
  * it is necessary to investigate potential fraud or security breaches;
  * it is for any other purpose to which you consent; or
  * otherwise as we are required or permitted by law.

We reserve the right to disclose any personal information as needed if such information is requested by law enforcement agencies or if we are requested to do so by law, regulation, court order, or by a government entity. We may also disclose your personal information to third parties if we have reason to believe that disclosing such information is necessary to: (i) conduct investigations of possible breaches of law; (ii) cooperate in any legal investigation; (iii) identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be violating the Terms of Use of this Website; or (iv) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property. In addition, we may disclose anonymous information to third-parties for marketing and other business purposes. For example, we may provide anonymous information to advertisers and commercial partners about the size and demographic composition of our user base.

We may feature contests, sweepstakes or other promotions on our Website from time to time. These promotions may require you to provide personal information in order to join and we may use this information to administer the promotion. With your consent, we may also use the information you provide to market our products and services to you. With your consent, we may also share this information with our partners who may use such information to communicate with you about the contests, sweepstakes or other promotions or their products and services.

With your permission, we may from time to time contact you with information on offers of goods and services, brochures, new products and forthcoming events. You can sign up for these communications when you register to use the Website, complete a transaction on the Website, or wherever we offer you the opportunity to sign up. You may opt-out of receiving marketing communications at any time by emailing [emailus@brightsparktravel.ca](mailto:emailus@brightsparktravel.ca) or by following the opt-out instructions in our marketing e-mails. Please allow us a reasonable time to process unsubscribe requests.

We appreciate your e-mailed feedback, questions and comments. Please see the “How To Contact Us” section of this Privacy Policy. If you e-mail us, we will keep a copy of your message until we have had an opportunity to address your concerns and may archive your message for a certain period of time or discard it once it is no longer needed.

Our website uses “cookies” - small files that permit our Website to identify your computer or mobile device on future visits. You can set your web browser to refuse cookies but certain features on our Website that use cookies may be unavailable.

We use cookies to keep track of the pages you visit on the Website and to store information about you or your preferences between visits to the Website.

We also collect anonymous information about your computer or mobile device when you use our Website, such its IP address, operating system and browser type. If you follow a link to our Website or use a search engine to access our Website, we may collect the address of the page or the search engine query that referred you to our Website. We use this information to help us operate and improve the Website and to understand how visitors find our Website. For example, if we determine that you are on a mobile device, we may refer you to the mobile version of our Website.

We also use your IP address to determine the general physical location of your computer or mobile device and the name of your internet service provider.

Certain pages on our Website contain cookies, “web beacons” (also known as Internet tags, pixel tags and clear GIFs) or tracking scripts. These cookies, web beacons or tracking scripts allow us to obtain information such as the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the cookie or beacon appears, the URL of the page on which the cookie or beacon appears, the time the page containing the beacon was viewed, and the type of browser used to view the page. We may use this information to make the material that appears on our Website, or in promotional material you have agreed to receive, more relevant to you based on your interests as established from the portions of our Website you view. To opt-out of this use, you may set your browser to reject cookies as described above, but certain features on our Website that use cookies may be unavailable.

For your convenience, we may provide links to other websites and web pages that we do not control. We cannot be responsible for the privacy practices of any websites or pages not under our control and we do not endorse any of these websites or pages, the services or products described or offered on such sites or pages, or any of the content contained on those sites or pages. Other websites may collect and treat information collected differently, so we encourage you to carefully read and review the privacy policy for each website you visit.

The Website integrates content from and links to social media platforms. We also maintain a presence on social media platforms. Please understand that these platforms are operated by third-parties and that your use of the platforms is subject to the terms of use and privacy policies established by their operators. Information you post on these platforms may, depending on your privacy settings, be publicly visible. We urge you to carefully consider what you post. If you do not want your personal information to become publically visible, do not post it on these platforms.

Some pages on the Website contain social features let you publicly post photos or messages. The information you post can be collected and used by people you do not know. We may also use information you post on these social areas of our Website for promotional purposes, and by posting material to these social features, you (and your parent/legal guardian on your behalf, if you are under the age of majority in your jurisdiction of residence) grant to Educatours a world-wide, perpetual, irrevocable, transferable, sub-licensable, royalty-free, non-exclusive, and unrestricted license to copy, reproduce, adapt, transmit, edit, modify, or otherwise use, publicly display, distribute, translate and create compilations and derivative works from, any and all such content (in any format or media) and waive all moral rights in and to all such content in favour of Educatours. We urge you to carefully consider what you post in social areas.

We may provide a custom portal for travelers and trip organizers. If you are part of a group trip, you, or your parent or guardian if you are a minor, understand and agree that your trip organizers can access your contact information and your account status. You can also access your personal profile. Trip sponsors and other travelers on your trip can view and post photos, blog entries. Information you post on our portal may be visible to other members of your trip. We urge you to carefully consider what you post.

We are committed to preserving online privacy for all of the visitors to our Website, including children. Our Website is not designed for children and we do not knowingly collect information about children under the age of 13 without the consent of their parent or guardian.

We have taken reasonable steps and have in place appropriate physical, organizational, and technological security measures to protect your personal information, including keeping your financial information private and safe. You acknowledge, however, that no transmission of data over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, despite our efforts. We cannot guarantee that such information will not be intercepted by third-parties. We retain personal information that we collect only as long as reasonably necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected or to meet any legal requirements. We have retention standards which meet these requirements. We destroy personal information when it is no longer needed for the purposes for which it was collected.

Personal information may only be accessed by persons within our organization, or our third party service providers, who require such access to carry out the purposes indicated above.  Personal information we collect is maintained with the source of the information on servers based in Jackson, MI, United States.  

Please be aware that your personal information may be transferred to, stored or processed in the United States, where our servers are located and our central database is operated, and where we may have third party service providers. The data protection and other laws of the United States might not be as comprehensive as those in your country. As a result, this personal information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in the United States according to its laws.   However, please be assured that we take steps to protect your privacy. By using this Website, our services or purchasing our products, you understand that your information may be transferred to our facilities and those third-parties with whom we share it as described in this Privacy Policy.

You have a right to request access to your personal information and to request a correction to it if you believe it is inaccurate. If you have submitted personal information to us and would like to have access to it, or if you would like to have it removed or corrected, please contact us using the contact information provided below.

We will use reasonable efforts to comply with your request; however, in some cases we may not be able to allow you to access certain personal information in certain circumstances, for example if it contains personal information of other persons, or for legal reasons. In such cases, we will provide you with a reasonable explanation of why it is not possible to grant access to your personal information.

We may change this Privacy Policy at any time and from time to time. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be either posted on our Website, brochure and/or made available on request. The most recent version of the Privacy Policy is reflected by the version date located at the bottom of this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is not intended to and does not create any contractual or other legal right in or on behalf of any party.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or would like to learn more about how we protect privacy, please contact our privacy officer at:

TUI Education NA

8 Essex Center Drive

Peabody, MA

02124

Privacy Policy: last updated May 13, 2013.
